# **SAVON HUYNH**

xqhuynh@gmail.com	612-386-7919	Lino Lakes, MN 55014
Portfolio Site	<u>LinkedIn</u>	<u>GitHub</u>

#### **BIO**

Educated and hardworking military veteran who loves to use technology to solve problems. My expertise lies within front-end web apps but I'm also capable of working on the backend. I'm a lifelong learner and I love to tackle new and exciting projects.

# **SKILLS**

- React
- Node.js
- Express.js
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL

- Git & GitHub
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Redux

- Material UI
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- Ajax

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# **Software Engineer Student**, Prime Digital Academy

March 2022 - Present

Minneapolis, MN

Solo Project: Sweet Surrender eCommerce Store

- Design wireframes using Figma and translate prototype to website design
- Create eCommerce web application using PERN stack in addition to Material UI, Passport, and Bootstrap within 2-week sprint

Client Project: Groupie Web Application

- Engage with client and provide prototype based on client specifications using Figma and present to client for approval
- Design web application within 2-week sprint utilizing PERN stack along with Amazon AWS,
  Google Maps and Google Places 3<sup>rd</sup> party API
- Present web application to client and other stakeholders after completion

#### Auto Body Estimator, Master Collision

October 2021 – March 2022

Minneapolis, MN

- Oversaw auto repairs from conception to completion utilizing various estimating and part sourcing software
- Developed store strategies to raise client pool, expand store traffic, and optimize profitability
- Communicated with all stakeholders through the repair process and set firm timelines for repair completion

**Federal Grants IT Intern**, U.S. Dept of Health and Human Services September 2021 – December 2022 Remote

- Assisted in the development of usable, accessible interfaces for HHS grants.gov website which allows for a streamlined grants management process
- Contributed to and maintained HHS grants GitHub repository

## Ramp Agent, Delta Airlines

March 2020 - October 2021

Minneapolis, MN

- Prepared, coordinated, and communicated with other departments for aircraft departure and arrival in a safe and timely manner in a fast-paced environment
- Cross-trained and contributed to the overall success of ramp operations

## Auto Body Estimator, Friendly Chevrolet

March 2019 - January 2020

Fridley, MN

- Compiled auto damage estimates for insurance companies and clients using estimating software and technology
- Communicated repair expectations: plan, monitor, evaluate, and review job orders

## **Customer Service Manager**, Abra Auto Body

January 2018 – September 2018

Roseville, MN

- Conducted daily meetings with technicians and estimators regarding daily goals and expectations
- Initiated and oversaw auto repairs for clients and insurance companies
- Contributed to the revenue growth of the shop to become the top two earners in the state

# Service Center Estimator, Progressive Insurance

July 2015 - January 2018

Burnsville, MN

- Utilized estimating and repair management software to determine damage quotes and assess repairability
- Streamlined the repair process with auto body shops thus cutting costs while increasing client satisfaction

#### **Console Operator**, United States Navy

January 2011 – January 2015

Norfolk, VA

- Supervised and trained crew members in the safe and efficient transport of over 1.3 million gallons of jet fuel
- Ensured the safe transport of jet fuel during refueling-at-sea and flight operations while maintaining speed and accuracy
- Trained and onboarded over 500 incoming sailors and scheduled onboarding events and activities

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Engineer, Prime Digital Academy

August 2022

Certificate of Completion

Minneapolis, MN

**Information Technology Management**, University of Minnesota

December 2021

**Bachelor of Science** 

Minneapolis, MN